我们本该去看摇滚演唱会的
We're supposed to be at a rock concert
可我却在这儿…看石头
but all I see is-- rock.
别急 神子
Relax, Miko.
演出还有两个小时才开始呢
The show doesn't start for two hours.
知道我为“歪猴子”乐队等了多久吗？
Do you know how long I've waited to see Slash Monkey?
呃…
Eh...
一辈子了！
Forever!
而且他们只来美国一次！
And it's their only U.S. date!
居然只来一次
There's a shock.
那个三流保加利亚嚎叫乐队 太不给面子了
I mean, who doesn't love obscure Bulgarian shriek metal?
从各方面来看 这个矿已经被采空了
By all appearances the mines' been stripped.
可我发现了一个信号
But I'm getting a signal.
虽然很微弱 但绝对是能量
It's faint, but it's definitely energon.
哇…
Whoa...
这不合常理
Doesn't make sense.
挖掘行动四五年前就终止了吧？
This operation's been abadoned four, maybe five years?
霸天虎从不落下一丁点儿能量
And Decepticons never leave energon behind.
呃 各位？
Eh, guys?
酷！
Cool!
她怎么进去了
She went in.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
真的？你还不了解她吗？
Really? Have you... met her?
呃 神子 快回来！
Eh, Miko. Get back here!
里面的东西应该挺有趣
It would be kind of interesting to see.
其实应该…
You know, if it were...
很安全？
Safe?
枯矿的架构很不稳定 杰克
A stripped mine can be structurally unstable, Jack.
我保证轻拿轻放
I promise to step lightly.
那就…别告诉你妈
Just... don't tell your mom.
啊 威震天陛下
Ah, Lord Megatron.
我决不是在以下犯上
Far be it from me to question your intentions
但我不明白 我们干嘛要偷偷摸摸地回到这个…老地方？
but I do not understand why we return here after all this time, alone?
我们榨干了矿里的最后一丝能量
Every last trace of energon was extracted from this mine.
什么都没留下
There is nothing left.
不要多嘴行吗 红蜘蛛？
Indulge me, Starscream, won't you?
神子
Miko!
- 神…
- Mi...
- 看看这里！
- Check it out!
在这儿排练再好不过了
Now, this would make an awesome rehearsal space.
你好！你好 克利夫兰
Hello! Hello Cleveland.
准备好摇滚了吗？
Are you ready to rock?
喔――哈――哇！
Whoooooohaaaaa... whoa!
阿尔茜 有发现
Arcee, found something.
隔板？隔板 你听见了吗？
Bulkhead? Bulkhead, do you read?
见鬼
Scrap.
地下矿藏对信号有干扰
The mineral composition down here is causing interference.
好吧 音效可能还不够完美
OK, maybe the acoustics aren't perfect.
就是这儿
Over here.
应该给老救带个样本
Ratch's gonna want a sample.
很有趣嘛
How intriguing.
呃…一群笨蛋！
Ehhhh, incompetent fools!
这套挖掘设备早该被调走了
This mining equipment should have been relocated.
怎么还在这儿？
Why is it still here?
问得好
A most valid question.
我很抱歉 主人
My apologies, master.
我记得负责调度的是声波
I believe Soundwave was in charge of coordinating transport.
不过说句实话
But in fairness
在您做星际旅行期间 我们都身兼数职
during your inter-stellar travels, we all had to assume additional responsibilities.
难免有些失误
Clearly, mistakes were made.
是的 难免
Yes, clearly.
这也叫榨干了？
Every last trace of energon extracted?
威震天陛下 我可以解释
Lord Megatron, I can explain.
解释什么？
Explain what?
解释你为什么私藏能量储备？
That you've been hoarding a supply of energon for your personal use?
不！不能这么说 您说过…
No! Not exactly. You said...
你当我是傻子吗 红蜘蛛？
Do not take me for a fool, Starscream!
我从一开始就知道你在打小算盘
I have been wise to your transgressions from the beginning.
你不但取走我胸口的黑暗能量
Not only did you pluck the Dark Energon from my chest
试图杀我而未遂
in a failed attempt to snuff my spark
还用它召唤了你自己的不死战士
but you tried to raise your own undead warrior with it.
你为此断臂的事情已经不再是秘密
It's no secret that you lost an arm in the process
尽管你修复得完好如初
which you've since had replaced.
这您都知道？！
You know about that?!
声波很擅长监视
Soundwave is quite competent in surveillance.
你大可放心
I can assure you.
事实上 红蜘蛛
The fact is, Starscream
尽管你在暗中捣鬼
despite your treachery
但我总是睁一只眼 闭一只眼
I've allowed you to carry on this long
因为看着你屡战屡败 也不失为一种乐趣
because I took a certain delight in following your string of failures.
可惜你越来越惹人讨厌 明知故犯
But you finally become tiresome, predictable.
你休想翻身了
You hit rock bottom.
主人 求求您！再给我一次机会！
Master, please! Give me one more chance!
我给您磕头！
I beg of you!
你对我已经毫无用处了 红蜘蛛
You have ceased to be of use to me, Starscream
所以 你就放心地去吧
so you shall simply cease to be.
蹲下！
Stay down!
红蜘蛛！你敢抛下我？
Starscream! You dare abandon me?
见鬼！
Scrap!
什么？不！
What? No!
阿尔茜？
Arcee?
阿尔茜！
Arcee!
噢 见鬼
Oh, scrap.
是我干的吗？
Did I do that?
我看不像
Don't think so.
你还好吗？
You OK?
好着呢 你呢？
Natch. What about you?
好得不得了…
Peachy...
喔…
Whoa...
别担心 神子
Don't worry, Miko.
我能顶住
I got it under control.
你知道为什么塌方吗？
What do you think caused the cavein?
天晓得
Who knows.
但愿阿尔茜和杰克都平安 因为…
I just hope Arcee and Jack are safe, 'cause...
我们肯定需要帮手
We can definitely use an assist.
你负责顶天立地 小隔
Just keep raising that roof, Bulk.
我来想办法出去
I'll get us outta here.
哈哈…明知故犯 主人？
Hahahaha... Predictable, master?
你就这么评价我吗？
Is that what you called me?
现在轮到谁翻不了身？
Well, now, who has hit rock bottom?
说什么？对不起
What's that? I'm sorry.
隔着一座五行山 我什么都听不清
I can't hear you beneath all that rubble.
哈哈…告辞了 威震天陛下！
Hahahaha... Farewell, Lord Megatron.
愿你一锈到底！
May you rust in peace!
不过 这种遭遇对你来说是小儿科
But you have survived far worse.
如果你自己逃了出来
If you managed to free yourself
就会怪罪我见死不救
you would blame me for your setback.
你发火的时候 我肯定会理亏
And there is no word that I could possibly escape from your wrath.
更不用说
Or worse yet
那些傻瓜随从肯定会来找你
your mindless followers will come looking for you
并因为营救你而立功
and take credit for your rescue.
这个功劳 应该属于我
Credit, that could rightfully be mine.
啊！威震天！
Ah! Megatron!
阿尔茜？
Arcee?
隔板？
Bulkhead?
神子？
Miko?
噢 那东西应该有用
Oh, that could come in handy.
神子
Miko.
我力大无穷
I'm feeling strong.
不 你不行了
No, you're not.
我只需要…休息一会儿…
I just need to... rest for a second.
就够了
That's all.
神子 听我说
Miko, listen to me.
这下面没有新鲜空气
There is no fresh air down here.
如果你消耗氧气太快…
If you use up the oxygen too fast...
我们会窒息！
We could suffocate!
不是我们 神子 是你！
Not we, Miko, you!
汽车人不需要呼吸 你忘了？
Autobots don't need to breathe, remember?
对啊！是从外太空降临的
Right! Smack down in outter space.
太厉害了…
That was cool...
好吧 要不我就…慢一点
OK, what if I just... slow down
减少…呼吸
breathe... less.
不 你必须立即住手
No. You need to stop, now.
不行 小隔
I can't, Bulk.
我必须救你出去
I have to get you out of here.
神子 拜托 别担心我
Miko, please, don't worry about me.
我很好
I'm fine.
出发
Roll out.
你听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
听起来像…
Sounds like...
钻探机
Drilling.
一定是阿尔茜和杰克
Got to be Arcee and Jack.
我们在…这儿！
We are in... here!
这儿…
Here...
神子 找个东西 砸我的脚
Miko, grab something, and bang it on my foot.
你能行吗？
Can you do that?
我不想伤着你
I don't want to hurt you.
我不是吹牛
I know it's hard to believe
我可是超级结实
but I'm tougher than I look.
用尽全力砸
Give it all you got.
我猜…
I suppose
帮助倒霉鬼脱困 是你最不想做的事
helping those less fortunate would be completely out of the question.
如果真的是那样
If that is the case
你可以用钻头把我杀掉
you might as well use your drill to finish me.
我保证 你以后再也不会有这么好的机会了
I guarantee you will never have a better opportunity than right now.
好了 你还等什么？
Well, what are you waiting for?
这是莫大的荣耀 机不可失！
Think of the glory--seize the day!
擎天柱会趁机动手的
Optimus would.
不 他不会
No, he wouldn't.
这是乘人之危
Not like this.
我一定会把今天的对话内容 一五一十告诉擎天柱――
I will be sure to share the details of our little conversation with Optimus--
然后扯出他的火种！
the day I rip out his spark!
好姑娘
That a girl.
刚才什么声音？
What was that?
没什么
Nothing.
来吧 继续砸
Go on, keep banging.
隔板 怎么回事？告诉我！
Bulkhead, what's happening? Tell me!
我的手臂…快撑不住了…
My arms... they're starting to give...
疼吗？
Does it hurt?
有点
A little.
隔板！
Bulkhead!
帮手来了
Help's coming.
我们得把他们引过来
We just got to guide them here.
再砸一次！
Hit me again!
神子 动手！
Miko, do it!
他们靠近了吗？
Are they any closer?
我听不出来
I can't tell.
这里的回声…
The sound is all...
太难听了！
freaky in here!
哈哈…太好了！
Hahaha, yes!
阿尔茜找到我们了！
Arcee found us!
哈哈哈…不要再质疑我的忠诚了…
Hahahaha... Put any doubt of my allegiance to rest.
他来干嘛？
What's he doing down here?
神子 躲到我身后 快！
Miko, get behind me, now!
哎呀呀 这不是隔板和他的宠物小臭虫嘛
Well, well, if it isn't Bulkhead and his pet vermin.
哎哟 看来你腾不出手了 是吧 汽车人？
My, you do have your hands full, don't you, Autobot?
要打就冲我来 红蜘蛛
Do whatever you want to me, Starscream.
先放人类走！
But let the human go!
不 我不离开你
No. I'm not leaving you.
看来 这个人类想留下
It appears that the human wishes to remain.
红蜘蛛 别逼我
Starscream, don't push me.
你喜欢跟大机器人一起玩 对不对 小姑娘？
You like playing with the big robots, don't you, little girl?
够了 汽车人！
That's it, Autobot!
我要…
I will...
什么？你要干什么？
What? You'll what?
让这块巨石砸到我们俩头上吗？
Maybe bring down the ceiling on top of all of us?
快跑 神子！
Run, Miko!
没错 跑吧 神子
Yes, run, Miko.
我想看看你如何逃命
I would love to see you try.
说真的 我想看看
Really, I would.
啊！
Ah!
杰克 带神子离开这儿 快！
Jack, get Miko out of here, now!
上来 上来！
Come on, come on!
快跑 神子！
Run, Miko!
我们不能丢下隔板！
We can't leave Bulkhead!
杀两个 赚一双
And then there were two.
阿尔茜会来救他的 对吗？
Arcee will save him, won't she?
趁威震天爬出来之前 我们俩得想办法逃出去
You and I just need to find a way out of here before Megatron digs himself free.
威震天也来了？
Megatron's here, too?
以为我会求饶吗 红蜘蛛
If you think I'm gonna beg for mercy, Starscream
省省吧！
forget it!
是啊 跪地求饶太丢脸了 不是吗？
Er, yes, begging for mercy would be quite pathetic, wouldn't it?
不过 把你活捉 我就立大功了
Well, you're much more valuable to me alive.
威震天该对我刮目相看 我不光救了他
Imagine Megatron's appreciation when I not only rescue him
还抓了个汽车人
but deliver a Autobot.
那样一来 我就可以重振雄风了
I believe that would restore my statue quite nicely.
别动 红蜘蛛
Don't move, Starscream.
嘿 小隔
Hey, Bulk.
嘿 小茜
Hey, Cee.
举起手来
Raise your hands.
噢…
Oh...
我们可以就地解决他
We could finish him, here and now.
可惜我没带手雷
Shame I didn't bring any grenades.
如果换成擎天柱 会下手吗？
Would Optimus finish them?
不 他多半不会
No, he probably wouldn't.
这是乘人之危
Not like this.
但擎天柱也不会救他们的 对吧？
But Optimus wouldn't rescue them, either. Right?
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
主人 您还活着！
Master. You are alive!
感谢火种源！
Thank the Allspark!
我没有抛下您 主人
I did not abandon you, master.
我回来…是要救您！
I returned... to save you!
救我？
Save me?
火种可鉴 威震天陛下
Look into my spark, Lord Megatron.
我是真心的！
My intentions were true.
求求您 发发慈悲吧！
Please, have mercy!